Email: enunes1@asu.edu **ERIC NUNES**

1215 E. Lemon Street, Apt #105, Tempe, AZ-85281

Website: https://efnunes.github.io/

SUMMARY

Computer Engineering Graduate student with 4 years' experience in research and development of data analysis tools. Hands-on experience with Python, R, SQL, C++, and MATLAB. Knowledgeable in processes and tools related to Big Data and Data Science.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Engineering **Present**

Arizona State University, AZ GPA: 4.0

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering May, 2012

Syracuse University, NY

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Telecommunication

June, 2010

University of Mumbai, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning: Classification, regression, clustering, anomaly detection, feature engineering, online learning, Experience with deep learning.

- **Programming Languages**: Python, MATLAB, C++, Prolog, HTML, and LaTeX. Familiar with C, R.
- Libraries: scikit-learn, ElasticSearch, Weka, Pandas, Theano, Caffe.
- Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.
- Big Data and Cloud: Splunk, Spark, Familiar with Big Data Processing Platforms: Hadoop and Cloud tools: Amazon S3.

KEY PROFESSIONAL AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist / Researcher, Cyber Reconnaissance Inc. (CYR3CON)

June 2016 - Present

Contact: 315-439-3089

Tools: Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Spark.

- Designed a system to store and mine data from darknet markets and forums.
- Leading a team of developers and analysts to build tools/products for security applications. In particular,
 - Leveraging threat intelligence to build learning models for predicting likelihood of exploitation of a vulnerability (vulnerability prioritization),
 - Providing intelligence on Mobile threats (both Android and iOS applications),
 - Active threat assessment on client systems,
 - Named-entity recognition (to determine vulnerable software) using RNN/LSTM seq2seq models,
 - Building classification models to identity malicious web scripts (PHP/HTML).
 - Assist with the expansion of CYR3CON future product features as well as the management and development of growing community of users, guiding/assisting them in trials and integrating with client systems.

Security Automation Intern (Data Science), PayPal

May 2017- August 2017

Tools: Python, Splunk, Spark.

- Analyzed user login activity using Akamai logs and enriched it with other data feeds such as threat intelligence, merchant data, credential dumps.
- Implemented operational Anomaly detection models to detect Account Takeover (ATO) attacks to raise alerts.
- Visualized ATO attacks in real time on a dashboard in Splunk to aid risk to flag fraudulent transactions.

Graduate Research Assistant, CySIS Lab, Arizona State University

August 2014 - Present

Tools: Python, PostgreSQL, Prolog, tcpflow.

- Modeling of threat actors: Identifying cyber adversaries using argumentation and machine learning models (knowledge base: 10 million attacks).
- Proactive Cyber-Threat Intelligence: Built a system to crawl and parse the Darknet (markets and forums) to extract cyber threat intelligence including zero-day exploits using data mining and machine learning techniques. Identifying targeted software through disclosed vulnerabilities on Darkweb.
- Malware task identification: Identifying the tasks that a piece of malware was designed to perform on the system (adversarial intent) using cognitive learning models.

PATENTS

- Systems and Methods for predicting which software vulnerabilities will be exploited by malicious hackers to prioritize for Patching, Submitted, 2017.
- Systems and Methods for Data Driven Malware Task Identification. Submitted, 2016.
- Intelligent darkweb crawling infrastructure for cyber threat intelligence collection. Licensed to CYR3CON, 2016.

REFERRED PUBLICATIONS

https://efnunes.github.io/publication.html